<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Purdue Academics</title>
    <link>https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/rss/academics.xml</link>
    <description>Purdue Academics RSS feed</description>
    <item>
      <title>More than 1,400 graduates celebrate their ‘comeback’ during Purdue Global commencement ceremonies </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2023/Q2/more-than-1,400-graduates-celebrate-their-comeback-during-purdue-global-commencement-ceremonies.html </link>
      <description>Lauren Castrinos Bradford had a short, simple thought as she navigated Purdue Global’s Master of Arts in psychology. “In a year, you’ll wish you had started now,” she told herself.  </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 19:00:00 EDT </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ranked No. 1, Purdue’s 100% online hospitality and tourism management master’s is a hot commodity </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2023/Q2/ranked-no-1-purdues-100-online-hospitality-and-tourism-management-masters-is-a-hot-commodity.html </link>
      <description>Sidelined by the pandemic and now bolstered by pent-up demand from folks who were stuck at home for years, the hospitality industry is back, with industry groups such as the American Hotel and Lodging Association predicting that 2023 will surpass pre-COVID-19 demand.  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 EDT </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concord Law School launches new class to address rural legal issues </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2023/Q2/concord-law-school-launches-new-class-to-address-rural-legal-issues.html </link>
      <description>Concord Law School at Purdue Global, Purdue’s online school for working adults, wants to solve the problem of “legal deserts” across the U.S.  </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 EDT </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purdue receives $10 million commitment from Blake family to establish ethics center in new Daniels School of Business </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2023/Q2/purdue-receives-10-million-commitment-from-blake-family-to-establish-ethics-center-in-new-daniels-school-of-business.html </link>
      <description>Purdue University has received a $10 million commitment from alumni Norman and Karen Blake to establish an ethics center within the Mitchell E. Daniels, Jr. School of Business.  </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EDT </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New assay accelerates E. coli testing process </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2023/Q1/new-assay-accelerates-e.-coli-testing-process.html </link>
      <description>A team led by Purdue University’s Bruce Applegate has developed a new time-saving assay to detect an especially severe strain of E. coli in ground beef.  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 EST </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purdue offering new fully online Master of Science in International Agribusiness </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2022/Q4/purdue-offering-new-fully-online-master-of-science-in-international-agribusiness.html </link>
      <description>Purdue University is offering a new fully online Professional Master of Science in International Agribusiness aimed at agribusiness professionals worldwide. Applications are being taken now, and the program launches in January 2023.  </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 11:00:00 EST </pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purdue Provost announces he will step down in December, search committee formed </title>
      <link>http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2022/Q4/purdue-provost-announces-he-will-step-down-in-december,-search-committee-formed.html </link>
      <description>Purdue University Provost Jay Akridge announced Tuesday (Nov. 8) his plan to step down at the end of December after serving more than five years as Purdue’s chief academic officer.   </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:00 EST </pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
