<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BookBrowse Book News</title>
    <link>https://www.bookbrowse.com/rss/book_news.rss</link>
    <description>BookBrowse Book News RSS feed</description>
    <item>
      <title> Film adaptation of Are You There God? It's Me, Margaret receives glowing reviews</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3072</link>
      <description> The long-awaited film adaptation of Judy Blume's novel Are You There God? It's Me, Margaret opened in theaters yesterday and is getting glowing reviews. Rotten Tomatoes' compilation of critics' reviews gives it a 99% positive rating; and audience reviews on the same site rate it 96% positive.

For over fifty years, Judy Blume's classic and groundbreaking novel has impacted generations with its timeless coming of age story, insightful humor, and candid exploration of life's biggest questions. In Lionsgate's big-screen adaptation, 11-year-old Margaret (Abby Ryder Fortson) is uprooted from her life in New York City for the suburbs of New Jersey, going through the messy and tumultuous throes of puberty with new friends in a new school. She relies on her mother, Barbara (Rachel McAdams), who is also struggling to adjust to life outside the big city, and her adoring grandmother, Sylvia (Kathy Bates), who isn't happy they moved away and likes to remind them every chance she gets.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 09:19:43 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Ada Limón appointed to second term as U.S. Poet Laureate</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3071</link>
      <description> Ada Limón, who has been the U.S. Poet Laureate for a two-year term, has been given a second two-year term, marking the first time in history that a U.S. Poet Laureate has been given two two-year terms. Limón's second term runs from September 2023 to April 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 08:06:33 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> PEN Report shows state legislation 'supercharging' book bans</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3070</link>
      <description> A new PEN America report documents how state legislation across the country is driving an alarming spike in book bans in schools.

The report, Banned in the USA: State Laws Supercharge Book Suppression in Schools, expands on two previous PEN America reports tracking the intensifying wave of book bans and laws aimed at limiting access to school and library books. Since July 2021, when PEN America began tracking public school book bans, the organization recorded more than 4,000 bans books through December 2022, including 1,477 individual book bans affecting 874 unique titles during the first half of the 2022-23 school year—a 28% increase over the previous six months.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:54:12 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Missouri House Republicans want to defund libraries. Here's why</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3069</link>
      <description> Missouri's Republican-led House voted to cut all funding for libraries in its version of the state's annual budget, an unprecedented move that has angered librarians and patrons across the state who rely on the facilities for everything from books to educational programming and internet access.

The proposal is not yet final; it now sits before the state Senate's appropriations committee along with the rest of the annual $45.6 billion budget, and Republican chair Sen. Lincoln Hough said it would be his intention to restore library funding.

But for those who manage or use the state's 160 library districts, especially in rural areas where services are not as robust, the threat feels real...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 23:24:08 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Harry Potter books to be made into new TV series</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3068</link>
      <description> The wizarding world of Harry Potter is to be brought to life in a new TV series starring a brand new cast.

The series will be based on author JK Rowling's books and will be produced over the course of a decade, with each series based on one of the seven books.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:49:21 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Texas county to consider shutting down library after book ban ruling</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3066</link>
      <description> April 11: After a federal judge ordered the return of more than a dozen books improperly pulled from the Llano County Public Library shelves for their content, the county's commissioners have called a special meeting for April 13 to discuss shutting the library down altogether.

According to a notice and agenda posted to the Llano County website, the Llano County Commissioners Court has set a meeting to discuss whether to "continue or cease operations of the current physical Llano County Library System," the continued employment of library staff, and the "feasibility of the use of the library premises by the public."

Apr 14: After a hastily called meeting (and with a crowd of library supporters rallying outside) Llano County Commissioners on Thursday decided not to pursue the closure of the county's public libraries—at least for now... in a statement released after the meeting, Llano County Judge Ron Cunningham lamented that "a public library simply cannot function if its librarians, county judge, commissioners, and even the volunteers who serve out the goodness of their heart, can be sued every time a library patron disagrees with a librarian's 'weeding' decision," and vowed to continue to fight for the right to ban books in the courts.

The drama in Llano County comes after a federal judge on March 30 found that the library board in Llano County infringed the constitutional rights of library users by unilaterally removing books it deemed inappropriate.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Crime writer Anne Perry dies aged 84</title>
      <link>http://www.bookbrowse.com/news/detail/index.cfm?news_item_number=3067</link>
      <description> Anne Perry, author of more than 100 novels that have sold more than 26 million copies worldwide died on April 10. She was 84.

Her work included two suspense series set in Victorian England: the William Monk novels and the Charlotte and Thomas Pitt novels. She also wrote a series of books featuring Charlotte and Thomas Pitt's son, Daniel; as well as the Elena Standish series, set during World War I; 19 Christmas holiday novellas; a historical novel, The Sheen on the Silk, set in the Byzantine Empire; and short stories. Her most recent novel is The Traitor Among Us, the fifth installment in the Elena Standish series, to be published in September.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 11:51:03 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
